



C Class WA Drivers Licence

Profile

I am currently employed by the Western Australia (WA) Police Force as the Policy Development Facilitator. I have over 13 years' experience with the agency, primarily in roles where I develop and implement business improvements for both operational and strategic areas.

My core competencies are:

Jessica Hek

- Strategic business improvement Use a range of information sources to conduct qualitative and quantitative analysis on potential issues, emerging trends and themes, risks, and areas of opportunity to conceptualise and develop business improvement strategies and plans.
- Stakeholder engagement Engage with a range of stakeholders to gain an understanding of key issues, map processes, and identify possible solutions. Build productive working relationships to guide, influence, collaborate, and negotiate business improvements.
- Research and evaluation Monitor program and policy performance to evaluate outcomes, measure success, identify shortcomings, and inform future business planning research, strategies, tools and methods.

Career Summary		
Senior Policy Development Facilitator Legislation and Policy WA Police Force	2 Months	2020 - 2021
Policy Development Facilitator Legislation and Policy WA Police Force	2 Years	2019 - Current
Business Practice Coordinator Business Intelligence & Analytics WA Police Force	6 Months	2018 - 2019
Coordinator Corporate Knowledge Legislation and Policy WA Police Force	6 Months	2017 - 2018
Knowledge Base Administrator State Communications Division WA Police Force	6 Years	2013 - 2019
CAD Support Officer State Communications Division WA Police Force	8 Months	2015 - 2018
Voice and Business Analyst State Communications Division WA Police Force	7 Months	2012 - 2013
Quality Assurance Officer State Communications Division WA Police Force	10 Months	2011 - 2012
Team Leader State Communications Division WA Police Force	1 Year	2010 - 2012
Customer Service Operator State Communications Division WA Police Force	4 Years	2009 - 2012
Data Entry Officer State Communications Division WA Police Force	1 Year	2007 - 2009

Jessica Hek Page 1 of 3

Relevant Experience

Policy Development Facilitator

Legislation and Policy | WA Police Force | January 2019 - Current | 2 Years

Contribute to the development and implementation of strategic, corporate and operational policy by,

- Researching and analysing legislation, social and political factors, trends, patterns, risks and emerging issues to provide advice and recommendations supported by evidence.
- Creating and maintaining networks and positive working relationships with internal and external stakeholders, to negotiate and influence change.
- Thinking laterally to conceptualise solutions, using my knowledge and experience to provide insight and advice on business improvement strategies.
- Drafting policy and procedures to align with overarching legislative requirements, government and agency strategic direction, and operational environment.
- Working collaboratively with my team and other stakeholders on the development of policy and maintaining a contemporary policy environment for the agency.
- Providing support, guidance and direction on the management of online content, to ensure agency policy and procedure are accessible to staff through the Corporate Knowledge Base.

Key Achievements

Contributing to the Policy Reform Project by:

- Developing a triage tool that identified and measured policy risks to assist in prioritisation and direction of work, e.g. the risk of injury, loss of reputation, or inability to perform business duties if the policy or procedure were incorrect, and the likelihood of these risks occurring, to produce a risk and impact rating.
- Developing the Policy and Corporate Knowledge Governance Framework.
- Creating reports, concept proposals, and decision sheets on the direction of the reform, for submission to our Corporate Board of executives.
- Creating and implementing communication strategies, plans and documents, project management tools, and templates.
- Conducting information sessions, workshops and meetings with key stakeholders to provide education on the reform, support business areas through change, and influence and embed cultural change.

Knowledge Base Administrator

State Communications Division | WA Police Force | February 2013 – January 2019 | 6 Years

Reviewed and developed business processes for the Police Communications Centre, State Communications Division. The Police Communications Centre contains the emergency and non-emergency call centre, and dispatch centre for police operations.

- Used quality assurance data to identify trends, patterns and emerging themes in business performance.
- Conducted research and analysis of legislation, state and agency policy, Memoranda of Understanding, and best practices to identify business requirements, obligations, and strategic direction.
- Collated and analysed qualitative and quantitative data to identify business risks, benefits, interdependencies, and recommendations for business improvements and processes.
- Defined business processes through process mapping, research, and analysis.
- Worked with stakeholders and subject matter experts to discuss business needs, issues, interdependencies, and potential solutions for negotiation. E.g. ensuring that investigating officers were able to complete their tasks based on the information and actions taken by our Customer Service Operators.
- Developed and implemented business processes for the division, in the form of guides, standard operating procedures, aide memoires, system and technology changes.
- Managed and monitored the communication and implementation of business improvement activities, to review program performance and measure success. E.g. conducting User Acceptance Testing, surveys, and reviewing quality assurance data to monitor progress and implementation.
- Provided advice, guidance and direction to Team Leaders and Customer Service Operators on the correct application of policy and procedure.
- Published business processes to various knowledge bases, using single-source principles.
- Ensured documents, assessments, reports, and approvals were appropriately recorded and stored

Jessica Hek Page 2 of 3

- Managed and maintained the functionality and appearance of multiple knowledge bases through content management systems, and using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Provided system support and training to my team and users of the knowledge bases.

Key Achievements

- Conceptualised, managed, and implemented a divisional project to secure new software and create three new knowledge bases for the Police Communications Centre. This project involved the review and amendment of every business process within the division, and alignment with changes resulting from the CAD P1 Project.
- Implemented a change champion process with a target group of stakeholders to develop positive working relationships and increase user buy-in.
- Created the team's current Style Guide, change management plans, and business continuity and disaster recovery plans.

Qualifications

Diploma of Leadership and Management Integral | 2020

Training and Education

HTML5 Coding Essentials and Best Practices W3C via edX | In progress

HTML & CSS Fundamentals

W3C via edX | 2021 | Web Certificate

Policy in Practice IPAA WA | 2020

Change Management

AIM | 2020

CSS Basics

W3C via edX | 2019 | Web Certificate

Policy Essentials

Public Sector Commission | 2019

Drawing Nature, Science and Culture (Illustration)

University of Newcastle via edX | 2017 | Web Certificate

JavaScript, HTML and CSS Web Development

Microsoft via edX | 2016 | Web Certificate

Systems and Software

Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, Teams, Outlook, Visio etc)

Atlassian JIRA project management software

Objective

HP Service Manager (SM9)Incident Management System (IMS)

SIMR / RMIS

Computer Aided Dispatch (CAD)

CAD Report Manager

Solidus telephony system

Call Line Identification (CLI) rolling screen for 000 calls

Madcap Flare content management system

Adobe RoboHelp content management system

Redbox audio recording software

NICE audio recording software

Global Management Technology (GMT) workforce scheduling software

Referees

Kylie George

Senior Policy Development Facilitator Legislation and Policy | WA Police Force 9222 1041

kylie.george@police.wa.gov.au

Karen McFarland

Former Assistant Director Policy Development Legislation and Policy | WA Police Force 0457 779 614

k.mcfarland@ecu.edu.au

Additional referees can be provided on request

Jessica Hek Page 3 of 3